# Joshua Martínez

Website: https://mynjj.github.io

## Profile

Hardworking passionate profesional, currently studying a Msc. in Computer Science. With experience in software development, which taught me to translate my hard-skills to useful products. Highly responsible on my work. Excited to learn more, try new things, face challenges, and to help.

#### EDUCATION

• IT University • Master of Science in Computer Science; Gr: 12/12	Copenhaguen, Denmark Aug. 2020 – Present
• Universidad La Salle • Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications; GPA: 4 (9.76/10.0)	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2012 – Nov. 2016
Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México  Bachelor of Mathematics	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2014 – Jul. 2018

## EXPERIENCE

• ABaCus DK
• Student Developer

Copenhagen, Denmark
Nov. 2020 - Present

Email: djoshuamartinezpineda@gmail.com

I learned to work in a different culture, exploring a software developed by several people, with different work styles. Employment is time limited, but I was able to contribute on the system. See recommendation attached.

• Features, bug fixes for main product: Wrote fixes for minor bugs. Also the frontend and backend for pages displaying statistics for the teacher and students. The project used PHP/Symfony, JS/React.

• TIDE
Software Engineer

Mexico City, Mexico

Jan. 2019 - Aug. 2020

I developed many useful skills, learned to deliver fully functional products and to take responsability for them as a team. Designed and implemented creative solutions with several technologies.

- Employee time clock: Raspberry Pi's with multiple identification and synchronization features. Integrated sensors SDK's (C/Java), implemented features for the main service (Node.js), and UI(React)
- Airport Lounge app: Android/iOS app with React Native. Several features, integrated to an existing backend and created a backend-for-frontend for other features (Node.js/sails.js). Other technologies used: Redux, Firebase FCM
- Scotiabank's online pride parade: Basic MMORPG for 2020's stay@home Pride Parade. AWS/EC2 instances running a Phaser.js game, connecting to WebSocket servers (Typescript). Redis used for chat features.
- **IOT devices monitor**: Utilities to provide software updates, remote SSH access and stats recopilation for remote technical support. Implemented features on both sides (Node.js, PHP/Symfony, React, Linux scripting).
- Coca-cola promotional game: Soccer game for marketing stands of Coca-cola running on Raspberry Pi's, controlled by a Wii controller. Created with Python/Pygame.
- Airport Lounge software: Software spanning several company areas. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).
- Restaurant software: Highly customized restaurant software. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).

VtSoftware

Playa del Carmen, Mexico Jun. 2017 - May 2018

 $Software\ Engineer$ 

I learned how to translate my academic knowledge to useful software. One of the most important skills I learned is to listen to the client requirements and design accordingly.

• Vacation Clubs Payroll Software: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and Vue.js, integrated to an existing sales system DB. Also wrote some SQLServer stored procedures.

• **Hotel Inventory Software**: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and jQuery.

# École de Technologie Supérieure

Montreal, Canada

Research Internship

Apr. 2015 - Jul. 2015

• Estimation of disparity on GPUs: Research on disparity estimation algorithms and implementation on Matlab and then using C/CUDA

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

• **Teaching activities**: Private tutor on mathematics and programming, mostly focusing on kids (from 9 to 16). Social Service as an English teacher for adults.

#### ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

- ANFEI's award: Highest GPA on engineering faculty. Graduated with Magna Cum Laude.
- Robotics Winter School. 2013: INAOE, Puebla, Mexico.
- Robotics competitions. 2011 2013: Participation on Robocup, LARC competitions with the school robotics team (Cyberlords). Istanbul, Turkey and Mexico City. Our team achieved good results.
- Programming competitions.: IEEExtreme Programming competitions. Good results on our region.

## SKILLS I'VE WORKED WITH

#### Programming Languages

### TECHNOLOGIES

JS, TS, Node.js, Python, C, Java, SQL, PHP, Matlab

- Frontend:: React, Redux, React Native, Vue.js, Phaser, eCharts.
- Backend:: Laravel, Symfony, Redis, Socket.io, Express, Sails.js
- Other:: Linux, Raspberry Pi, AWS, Git, SVN, Ng-inx

# OTHER SKILLS (COURSEWORK & OTHERS)

Scala, C++, Microchip PIC Assembler, Arduino, Eagle.

## Languages

• Spanish: Native

• English: Fluent. TOEFL iBT(115/120)